I am a full stack software engineer with 5+ years of experience. I am fluent in Angular, Node.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, AWS architecture, EC2, RDS, Linux, SQL, redux, Objection.js ORM, Swagger/OpenAPI, git, Jenkins CI/CD, HTML, CSS, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, React.js, Python, Web Audio API, and PHP. I have participated in all phases of designing, developing, testing and deploying a large-scale enterprise web app through dozens of successful releases. My goal is to work with a team I love; develop products that excite me and have a positive impact; and learn continuously.

Professional Experience

productOps, Full Stack Software Engineer, 2014 - 2019

- Built web apps and SaaS plugins with Angular front-end and Node.js Express back-end.
- Learned whatever tools necessary from project to project to deliver quality software on time.
- Lead team conversations at all levels, from database schema with engineers to product strategy with clients. Participated in code reviews.
- Developed best practices for browser testing, integration testing, and git VCS merge process.
- Improved company culture and team productivity Facilitated engineering "book club" to study and discuss SW engineering topics, one-chapter-per-week. Developed & delivered new-hire trainings to cultivate a collaborative engineering culture.

MapR Technologies, Sr. Curriculum Developer, 2012 - 2014

- Created curriculum for Apache HBase NoSQL database, including Java programming labs.
- Assisted in curriculum design and review for Java-based MapReduce programming course.
- Developed class lab environment in AWS to spin up/down 10-node Hadoop clusters on demand.
- Managed on-boarding and ramp-up plans for 6 new hires to MapR's education team.
- Researched and wrote technical documentation for all aspects of MapR's Hadoop distribution.
- Wrote Confluence Wiki plug-ins to programmatically render docs pages.

Marichiba Consulting, Web Developer & Project Manager, 2008 - 2012

Managed projects and programs for clients lacking time, capacity, or know-how.

- MobileMakerz Prototyped a service to create mobile mini-apps for restaurants, implemented in PHP, HTML5, CSS and jQuery Mobile. Interviewed customers to gather requirements, and generated sales and marketing material.
- Hunter Finnell Media Designed and developed website and WordPress blog, showcasing the company's services with rich embedded video. Wrote all web copy. Administered the website and YouTube channel.
- In3 Finance Designed and developed website. Turned around a complete website in under three weeks, focusing on polished, established image for a financial services company.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Engineering and Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Minnesota, Duluth – Graduated magna cum laude. Minor in Mathematics.

MBA in Sustainable Management

Presidio School of Management, San Francisco, CA